Guide to the Charles A. Baylis Papers, 1924-1973
Duke University. University Archives
Charles A. Baylis papers 1924-1973
Duke University. University Archives
Baylis, Charles Augustus, 1902-.
4.5 linear feet Extent: 3600 Items
Charles A. Baylis was a professor of philosophy at Duke University from 1952-1970. This collection contains the correspondence, writings, personal papers, and departmental records. The material ranges in date from 1924-1973, bulk from 1950-1970.
UA.29.02.0003
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Charles A. Baylis Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1975.
Biographical Note
Charles A. Baylis (1902-1975) received degrees from University of Washington (A.B., A.M. 1924) and Harvard University (Ph.D. 1926) in Philosophy. He was a Senior Fulbright Scholar and a Guggenheim Fellow from 1958-1959.
Baylis held teaching positions at Brown University, from 1927-1949, and University of Maryland, from 1949-1952, before coming to Duke. He taught at Duke from 1952-1970 and was chairman of the Philosphy Department at Duke from 1956-1968.
Baylis was a member of the Association for Symbolic Logic, Southern Society for Philosophy and Psychology, American Philosophical Association, and the North Carolina Philosophical Society. He died in 1975 at the age of 73.
Collection Overview
This collection is organized into two series, correspondence and personal papers, and covers the years from 1924 to 1973. The bulk of the material is personal correspondence between Baylis and colleagues at other universities. Other material includes papers relating to groups and organizations that Baylis belonged to, course exams and syllabi, and essays he wrote. Notable in this collection is Baylis' Masters Thesis (1924) and a tenure case involving a colleague at the University of Washington (1948).
Subject Headings
Baylis, Charles Augustus, 1902-; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University. Dept. of Philosphy
Related Material
Biographical Reference Collection, 1972 – 2004
Duke University Archives
News Service Biographical Files, circa 1930s - 2004
Duke University Archives
University Archives Photograph Collection, 1861-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence, (2.25 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1925-1949 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1956 Jan.-May (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1956 June (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1956 Jul.-Dec. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957 Jan.-Feb. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957 Mar.-Apr. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957 May-Aug. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957 Sept.-Dec. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1958 Jan.-Mar. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1958 Apr.-Dec. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959 Jan.-Mar. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959 May-Dec. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960 Jan.-Feb. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960 Mar.-Jun. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960 Jul.-Oct. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960 Nov.-Dec. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1961 Jan.-Feb. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1961 Mar.-May (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1961 Jun.-Oct. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1961 Nov.-Dec. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1962 Jan.-Mar. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1962 Apr.-Jun. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1962 Jul.-Oct. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1962 Nov.-Dec. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963 Jan. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963 Feb. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963 Mar.-May (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963 Jun.-Sept. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963 Oct.-Dec. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964 Jan.-Feb. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964 Mar.-May (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964 Jun.-Oct. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964 Nov. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1965 Jan.-Mar. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1965 Apr.-Dec. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1966 Jan.-Oct. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1966 Nov.-Dec. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1967 Jan. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1967 Feb.-Mar. (Box 2)
- Papers, Groups, Departmental Business, (1.25 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1967 Apr.-Sept. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1967 Oct.-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1964, Undated (Box 3)
  - C.I. Lewis Papers (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - C.I. Lewis Papers (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Washington Tenure Case, 1948-1950 (Box 3)
  - N.C. Philosophical Society (Box 3)
  - Southern Society for Philospohy and Psychology, 1953-1956 (Box 3)
  - Southern Society for Philosophy and Psychology, 1957-1973, Undated (Box 3)
  - Association for Symbolic Logic, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
  - Association for Symbolic Logic, 1956-1967, Undated (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Association for Symbolic Logic, 1956-1967, Undated (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - American Philosophical Association, 1966 (Box 3)
  - American Philosophical Association, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Financial Papers, 1949-1970 (Box 3)
  - Professor Baylis' Writings, 1924-1963 (Box 3)
  - Professor Baylis' Writings, Undated (1 of 4) (Box 3)
  - Professor Baylis' Writings, Undated (2 of 4) (Box 3)
  - Professor Baylis' Writings, Undated (3 of 4) (Box 3)
  - Professor Baylis' Writings, Undated (4 of 4) (Box 3)
  - Course Enrollment, 1949-1965 (Box 3)
  - Professor Baylis' Course Exams and Syllabi, 1953-1967, Undated (Box 3)
  - Joint Duke-UNC Colloquia, 1959-1966, Undated (Box 3)
  - Philosophy Deptartment Business, 1947-1968 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Philosophy Deptartment Business, 1947-1968 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Philosophy Department Census Reports, 1961-1967 (Box 3)
  - Philosophy Department Courses, 1952-1967 (Box 4)
  - Philosophy Department Courses, Undated (Box 4)
  - Faculty Salary and Promotion Recommendations (Box 4)
  - Budget Requests, 1953-1965, Undated (Box 4)
  - Philosophy Department Meetings, 1947-1970 (Box 4)